ORIOL CASTRO

uri@oriolcastro.me
www.oriolcastro.me
@oriolcastro_

Profile

When I was a child I discovered that I had the need to understand how my surroundings worked and how I could use it to change and improve reality. This ignited my passion for science and technology. Alongside this path, I have been very active in many associations and social activism movements trying to generate synergies between the two worlds that I think are complementary. I am convinced that in good hands, technological advances are the tool to make people more free and conscious, and every day I work to fulfill this vision.

Experience

April 2017 - Abril 2019 Front-end web developer

Freelance www.okstudio.tech

Abril 2019 - Presently Front-end web developer

Xceed, Barcelona www.xceed.me

Education

January 2017 - Presently Online training as front-end developer

Codeacademy / Udacity / Self-taught

2011 - 2014 Master's Degree in Aerospace Science and Technology

Polytechnic University of Catalonia (Spain)

2005 - 2009 Aeronautical Technical Engineering esp. Aircraft

navigation

Polytechnic University of Catalonia (Spain)

Skills

I have the ability to manage my time efficiently and this allows me to work both individually and inside a team. I tend to communicate myself in an assertive way and I can assume leadership positions in a solvent way. Speaking and presenting in public has always been one of my strengths, I am proficient at synthesizing ideas and issuing key messages, as well as create motivation and share it.

It has always been easy for me to learn new programming languages, use new development tools or innovative technological concepts.

I'm a native Catalan and Spanish speaker, and I have a full professional competence level in English.